RYAN LAM

285 Milliken Meadows Drive, Markham, Ontario Ryanlam88369200aa@gmail.com (647) - 890 - 3817

WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-founder – PolyMask (Link ↗)

March 2020 - Present

Co-founded an early-stage medical device startup to help provide NIV treatment to COVID-19 patients using an aerosolization-proof mask. PolyMask has received seed funding and is backed by 2 non-profits. PolyMask is currently working with startup incubators for summer 2020. I'm in charge of supply chain logistics and work with potential investors.

Marketing Assistant - CDI Technologies

September 2018 – January 2019

Worked and aided with the re-branding of CDI Technologies. Performed Ed-Tech market research, built marketing campaigns and worked with CRMs.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Consulting − Kidogo (Link ↗)

March 2020

Kidogo is a social enterprise that provides early childhood care in Kenya. My team and I were challenged to help Kidogo find a method to increase revenue while maintaining high-quality education. My team and I proposed the idea of a franchise business model to allow Kidogo to partner with individually owned childcare centres. Doing so would increase their market share at a low cost.

Pomelo Business Plan − 2020 DECA EIP Provincials (Link 7)

February 2020

Pomelo was a business plan for an app that was designed to help users track their calorie intake via a picture. Its software would leverage ML, AI, and AR technologies to accurately predict the calories within a food item.

Consulting – Sidewalk Labs (Link ↗)

December 2019

My team and I were challenged to help Sidewalk Labs find a method to provide affordable housing in Downtown, Toronto while maintaining a high quality of life. My team and I proposed the idea of using laneway suites, robotic furniture, and panelized construction to cost-effectively build open floor houses.

ABOUT

I'm currently a grade 12 student from Markham with interests in STEM and Business. My goal in life is to build a startup (hopefully unicorn company) and make something significant to change the world.

During my high school years, I started multiple side hustles and worked with various non-profits. I enjoy reading nonfiction books, writing articles on Medium and working on MOOCs. I also complete in competitions including pitching comps, hackathons, and case studies.

I enjoy learning about physics, mathematics and computer science. I can currently code in Python, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. My main focuses are in Quantum Computation (Qiskit) and Artificial Intelligence (Pytorch, TensorFlow). I've also been invited to MIT to compete in their quantum hackathon and was given exclusive access to their library of professional development courses.

SOCIAL

Personal Website 7

LinkedIn 7

EDUCATION

Unionville High School

September 2016 - Present

Enrolled in the Business SHSM program and working towards an OSSD.